Ethan first saw them on a lonely stretch of road just past dusk.
At first, they looked like nothing more than shadows—cattle standing stiff on the ridge, a lone figure in a wide-brimmed hat among them.
But then he saw their eyes.
Glowing.
Watching.
Waiting.
An icy shiver crawled up his spine.
He told himself it was just a trick of the light, just the way the sun caught their eyes.
But something deep in his gut told him to drive faster, to put as much distance between himself and that field as possible.
Yet, no matter how fast he went, the feeling followed him home.
That night, he lay in bed, staring at the ceiling, unable to shake the image of those eyes.
The way they hadn’t just reflected the light, but burned with something deeper—something alive.
Then he realized something.
The glowing eyes hadn’t been in his rearview mirror.
They had been reflected in his windshield.
Watching him from the passenger seat.
Ethan barely slept.
The next day, he went back—he had to prove to himself it was nothing.
He pulled up to the field just as the sun dipped below the hills.
The cattle were there, standing as still as tombstones.
The figure was there, too.
Waiting.
He gripped his phone and climbed over the rusted barbed wire.
The wind whistled through the grass.
The trees creaked.
Somewhere, a crow let out a harsh caw.
He took a cautious step forward, lifting his phone to snap a picture.
Then he noticed the fence post beside him.
There was something resting on it—a skull, picked clean and grinning wide.
Ethan’s breath hitched.
He spun around.
The cattle had moved.
They were closer now, their burning eyes fixed on him.
The figure in the hat turned its head, slow and deliberate.
The shadows seemed to stretch and twist around it, swallowing the last light of the day.
Ethan ran.
He scrambled over the fence, bolted to his car, and tore down the road without looking back.
He didn’t stop until he was home, slamming the door shut behind him, chest heaving.
He laughed, shaking his head.
Just his imagination.
Just shadows and tricks of the mind.
Then his phone buzzed.
A new photo had been taken.
Hands trembling, he opened his gallery.
It wasn't the picture he had taken.
It wasn’t the cattle, or the field, or the figure in the hat.
It was a photo of his bedroom.
A photo of him.
Asleep.
And in the corner of the room, nearly swallowed by the darkness—
Two glowing eyes.
Watching.
Waiting.